# SAURABH PATIL

# Hotel manager in Treebo hotels and Experienced Front Office Executive Professional having 3 years experience

Address 2 Dnyanai apt nr union bank Kamatwade Ambad link road Nasik 422008

Phone 9766027542

E-mail saurabhpatildxb@gmail.com

**Date of birth** 1991-11-21

Passport no L7070519



A courteous, polite and well spoken hotel receptionist who is highly efficient and has excellent organisational skills. Possessing a good team spirit, deadline orientated and having a passion for providing the highest standards of hospitality and service to guests. Helpful and approachable but also commercially minded and having the ability to promote hotel facilities and maximise sales opportunities at all times. A quick learner who can absorb new ideas, communicate clearly and effectively and also find suitable solutions to meet the needs of guests. Keen to find a suitable position within an ambitious hotel where I will be able to continue to increase my work experience & develop my abilities

## Experience

## 2017-09 - present

## **Hotel Manager**

Treebo Hotels Nasik

- 1) Audit properties to check for revenue inclusion of both Treebo and hotel bookings.
- 2) inspect properties on a daily basis for proper functioning and adherence to standards
- 3) Ensure a great customer experience and minimize customer escalations.
- 4) Check inventory of toiletry stocks and place order for replenishment
- 5) Manage relations with owners to ensure transformation changes needed on operational basis
- 6) Customer Retention and Relationship building
- 7) Conducting Customer Delight Activities
- 8) Train Front Office to convert walk-in booking

### 2016-10 - 2017-07

## **Front Office Executive**

Hotel Suresh Plaza Nasik

- 1) Maintained an updated database of guest check-ins checkouts and fees.
- 2) Responded to guest complaints in a professional courteous manner.
- 3) Managed multiple phone lines while attending to guest issue
- 4) Maintained an updated inventory of front office supplies
- 5) Coordinated with other staffing departments to ensure solid guest relations
- 6) Handling daily petty cash, negotiation with vendors, and administration duties
- 7) Performed check-in and check-out activities for an average of 35 guests per shift
- 8) Generation of revenue reports on daily basis.
- 9) Maintain an inventory of vacancies reservations and room assignments
- 10) Register arriving guests and assign rooms
- 11) Compile and check daily record sheets guest accounts receipts and vouchers using computerized systems
- 12) Processed all guest reservations including guest follow up obtaining all necessary information and accurately entering it into computer system

### 2014-01 - 2016-01

## **Front Office Executive**

Hotel Royal Heritage Nasik

1) Welcoming guests to the hotel in a polite, friendly and helpful manner.

- 2) Dealing with late arrivals and assisting with early check-outs.
- 3) Check out departing guests using the hotel's accounting system.
- 4) Taking payment from guests in the form of cash or credit cards.
- 5) Answering telephone inquiries promptly & professionally & transferring calls on.
- 6) Being a point of contact for guests should they have any queries.
- 7) Arranging for brief tours of the hotels rooms and facilities.
- 8) Operating switchboard and directing calls appropriately.
- 9) Dealing with and resolving customer complaints.
- 10) Checking function sheets.
- 11) Managing group bookings for conferencing, the restaurant and accommodation.
- 12) Keeping up to date on all hotel products, services, pricing & promotional offers.
- 13) Completing the night auditing procedures with accuracy and attention to detail.
- 14) Maximise sales revenues through up selling and marketing programmes.
- 15)Provide information and literature about the hotel in person and via telephone.
- 16) Ensuring all relevant paperwork has been completed in order for a smooth handover at the end of your shift.

#### 

Kulkarni and Kulkarni co

1) Vouching of Cash and Bank books, Sales and Purchase register, Debtors ledger, Creditors ledger so as to authenticate the figures appearing in

Account books of the client.

2) Assist with preparation and co ordination of the audit process in audit period Attended important seminars on behalf of the office with Senior

Accountant and implemented the knowledge and strategies in the office. Served as Front desk executive and office executive and had meets with

the client Supporting to the team member.

- 3) Served as Front desk executive and office executive and had meets with the client
- 4) Supporting to the team member

#### 

Aurangabadkar and Associates

- 1) Maintaing the accounts, databases and daily billing up to date daily Recording cash transaction in cash book daily and also retaining the Petty cash book Involved in quarterly submission of physical inventory of CC limit Banking and other outside duties according to the need and requirement of the organisation.
- 2) Recording the entries in the software daily of cash, bank, purchases, sales and other expenses of the client at the client place.

#### 

- S S Mutha and CO
- 1) Maintain the books of accounts in Tally software.
- 2) Making cheques for the parties.
- 3) Ensuring the accuracy of daily transaction posted in the system
- 4) Admin work for the office.
- 5) Quick response to query mails Regularly attending the team meeting.

## Education

## 2017-10 - present MBA (HOSPITALITY AND HOTEL MANAGEMENT)

Doing Distance MBA which is expected to completed in October 2018 and also 1st sem marks 78%

## 2009-04 - 2012-04 B.COM

Completed B.com with Accounts and Audit as the main subjects and secured 60%

## 2018-03 - 2018-06 Hotel Receptionist and Opera PMS Hotel Booking software

## Skills

Front Office Managament	•••••
Customer Service	•••••
Guest experiences	•••••
Reservations	•••••
MS Windows / Office	•••••
Resolving guest disputes	••••